# Aasif Rahman M

Python Developer, India

Mail: asifrahman15@gmail.com

Phone / Whatsapp: +91 8056371496

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/aasif-rahman

GitHub: https://www.github.com/asifrahman15



### **Summary**

I am a software developer with more than 3 years of full time experience and 1 year of part time experience with various tools and technologies. My area of expertise was Python scripting, custom logics building and API based backend designing. My passion is to keep on exploring new technologies, tools and gadgets.

### **Experience**

# • Software Development Engineer – I

AutoGrid India Pvt. Ltd.

February 2023 - Present (1 Year)

Custom scripts development, Docker and Kubernetes, testing and debugging Python scripts and modules.

# Software Developer and Consultant

Self Employed (Freelance)

May 2022 - February 2023 (9 Months)

Worked on React web apps for Business application, Microservices development, Celery and Django based automation tools, mobile automation tools with Optical Character Recognition (OCR) & Android Debug Bridge (ADB) and worked on Cloud services such as AWS Lambda and EC2.

# Software Development Engineer

Decision Point Pvt. Ltd.

Nov 2021 - May 2022 (6 Months)

Worked on building Business analysis tools with the Data Science team, Microservices development, OAuth and worked on cloud services such as AWS Lambda, S3, EC2 and Azure Functions.

### Junior Software Developer and System Admin

Self Employed (Freelance)

January 2021 - November 2021 (11 Months)

Worked on Python and shell scripts, Django web apps with REST API, React app with Kafka, Telegram bot designing for advertising and broadcast, custom logic buildings, Python teaching, customised PC buildings and system service.

#### System Service, Custom PC Building and Assembly

Self Employed - (Part Time Freelance)

January 2020 - December 2020 (1 Year)

Computer hardware service, custom PC buildings and upgrading, OS Installation, local server configurations, remote access configuration for local servers, NAS building, local media server with Plex.

### **Recent Projects**

#### Mobile Automation Tools

An android automation tool for a specific repeated task with Optical Character Reading (OCR) & Android Debug Bridge (ADB). Dynamically written in such a way that the same tool can be used for any devices and any other purposes as well with minimal or no changes in configurable json.

### • E-Commerce Bot with Django Backend for Telegram

A Telegram bot with a django API backend for a E-Commerce company in a SaaS Model, In which the telegram users can apply for a dealership, after admin approval dealers can post their products on various categories with image and caption along with price. Users can see and buy products from the Dealers. Special Features in the system are Cart, Invoice, Wallet. Technologies used are Django ORM, Telebot (Python Library).

### Telethon Automation Web Apps

A Web app in which a group of Telegram Accounts can be Automated to join and leave on a specific group or channel based on the selection and count. Technologies used are Telethon (Python Library), AWS Lambda, Django Rest Framework Backend and Basics UI with React.

# E-Board with Web App

An IoT based home automation and controller using arduino and Web App Interface. The project is to convert all the existing conventional home appliances and devices into smart devices, which can be monitored, controlled and automated from anywhere in the world through a modern Web App which is built as a SaaS Model. Technologies used are Arduino (Hardware), Transducers, Django, Socket Connection (Channels).

# • Wearable Live Health Monitoring Gadget

An IoT based wearable live health monitoring gadget. The project is to monitor an elderly people with the fall detection system. Since it is a web app it can be used from

anywhere in the world. Also which is built as a SaaS Model. Technologies used are Arduino (Hardware), Transducers, Django, Socket Connection (Channels).

#### **Education**

- Bachelor of Technology (Electronics and Communication Engineering)
  Pondicherry University (2017 2021) 8.32 CGPA.
- Higher Secondary (Bio-Mathematics)

Tamilnadu State Board (2015 – 2017) - 78.92%.

High School

Tamilnadu State Board (2015) - 93.8%.

#### **Technical Skills**

- Python, Data Structure and Object Oriented Programming Knowledge.
- Django Framework with REST API, Pandas, ADB.
- C, C ++ and Basic SQL.
- Frontend Development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery Basics and React JS Basics).
- Complex Problem Solving and Quick Algorithm Designing.
- Familiar with Linux and Terminal (CLI).
- Computer Hardware and Software Service and Networking knowledge.
- Basic Knowledge of Networking, Basic Proficiency in the software Multisim, MatLab,
  Proteus Design Suite, Keil μVision IDE, Photoshop and Pinnacle.

#### Other Skills

Ability to make quick decisions and work independently, Adaptability to new things, Ability of critical thinking, Leadership Quality.

#### **Hobbies**

Bike Riding, Travelling, Coding Games, Building PCs and Electronic Projects, Going to Gym, Chess, Listening Music, Reading, Teaching.

#### **Declaration**

I hereby declare that the information given above is true to the best of my knowledge.